O.k., so now that we know the footwork, we're going to show you how to do the in and out together.
The first version of the in and out, is a one handed in and out.
O.k., so in order to get into the proper position we're going to do a transition with a cross body lead.
So after we do our basic we're going to do a cross body lead, one, two, three, we're going to cross, five, six, on seven we're going to switch hands.
So basically you have her hand in your left hand, you're going to hand it over to your right hand.
What you want to avoid doing is bringing the left hand over here to the right hand because that makes the girl feel like she's supposed to turn.
So instead you want to just meet the hands in the middle just like you were shaking hands.
O.k.?
So we have cross body lead, one, two, three, five, six, switch.
So now you're right to right.
Here, we are going to do an open break, so we'll push on one, pull on two, now here's what we want to do we want to pull the girl forward and make her turn at the same time.
So you want to pull her this way and let go.
So this is push, pull let go, and then you're going to stop her on the hip.
So basically you want to get her started turning but then you want to stop her before she turns too far.
So you want to end up right behind her.
This is push, pull, stop her, o.k.?
Your fingers are wrapped around in front of her hip bone, not here where you're going to tickle her but down here on her hip bone.
That way if she tries to turn too much you're holding her back.
So this is three, ladies, we want to keep our arms at home base so that we're not getting in his way blocking the hip.
So this is three, now again this is an inside turn so it follows the same patterns as the other inside turns.
We're going to push her forward on five, turn her on six, catch her on seven.
So the right hand pushes her that way on five, the left hand catches her and gives her a turn on six and then we use the right hand to catch her on seven just like before behind the back, ladies that's your cue to get your arm up and over.
So all together it looks like this.
We give a cross body lead, switch the hand on seven, push, pull and stop her, now, push, turn, and catch and basic, two three, five, six, seven.
Ladies you also have a couple of options with your arm styling.
On three, you can take the arms out if you want to.
You can also take them up, and guys if she does that, instead of using the shoulder, you just use the hip.
So it would look like this, five, six, seven, one, two, three, five, six, seven.